<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Panama City Beach on ThePointsPup</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/panama-city-beach/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Panama City Beach on ThePointsPup</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/panama-city-beach/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Jacksonville to Panama City Beach: A Pet-Friendly Road Trip Guide</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/jacksonville-to-panama-city-beach-road-trip/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/jacksonville-to-panama-city-beach-road-trip/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The drive from Jacksonville to Panama City Beach is about 5-7 hours depending on how many stops you make — and if you&amp;rsquo;re traveling with a dog, you&amp;rsquo;re going to make a lot of stops. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I learned driving this route with Ansel, my 70-pound GSP/Lab mix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Planning a PCB trip? Check out my full &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/embassy-suites-pcb-review&#34; &gt;Embassy Suites Panama City Beach review&lt;/a&gt; for the hotel details.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-route&#34;&gt;The Route
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;From Jacksonville (I started in Callahan), you&amp;rsquo;ll take I-10 West through Lake City, Tallahassee, and then head south on US-231 into Panama City Beach. It&amp;rsquo;s mostly highway driving with plenty of rest areas along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Distance:&lt;/strong&gt; ~350 miles&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Drive time:&lt;/strong&gt; 5-7 hours (with dog stops)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;best-stops-along-the-way&#34;&gt;Best Stops Along the Way
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-must-stop-busy-bee&#34;&gt;The Must-Stop: Busy Bee
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you only make one non-potty stop, make it &lt;strong&gt;Busy Bee&lt;/strong&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s basically Florida&amp;rsquo;s answer to Buc-ee&amp;rsquo;s — spotless restrooms (seriously, some of the cleanest gas station bathrooms you&amp;rsquo;ll ever see), a huge selection of snacks, jerky, fudge, and their famous Bee Bites. There&amp;rsquo;s also a Burger King and Dunkin&amp;rsquo; inside if you need real food.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two locations on I-10:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Live Oak&lt;/strong&gt; (Exit 283) — about 1.5 hours from Jacksonville&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lake City&lt;/strong&gt; (US-41 near I-75) — slightly earlier if you&amp;rsquo;re coming from the Callahan area&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both have plenty of room to walk your dog around before heading back on the road. It&amp;rsquo;s worth the stop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;rest-areas&#34;&gt;Rest Areas
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Florida&amp;rsquo;s I-10 rest areas are well-maintained with grassy pet areas:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Suwannee County Rest Area&lt;/strong&gt; (Mile Marker 294) — Good first stop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Madison County Rest Area&lt;/strong&gt; (Mile Marker 265) — Midway point&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leon County Rest Area&lt;/strong&gt; (Mile Marker 194) — Just west of Tallahassee&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All have pet areas, restrooms, and vending machines. Nothing fancy, but they get the job done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;coming-soon-buc-ees&#34;&gt;Coming Soon: Buc-ee&amp;rsquo;s
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Buc-ee&amp;rsquo;s is building a massive 75,000 square foot location near Tallahassee on I-10. Once that opens, it&amp;rsquo;ll be another great option. For now, Busy Bee has you covered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-i-packed-and-what-id-do-differently&#34;&gt;What I Packed (And What I&amp;rsquo;d Do Differently)
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-worked&#34;&gt;What Worked
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Backseat cover&lt;/strong&gt; — Non-negotiable. Keeps the car clean and gives your dog a non-slip surface.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Travel water bottle with attached bowl&lt;/strong&gt; — Perfect for rest stops without digging through bags.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Extra poop bags&lt;/strong&gt; — I always overpack. Running out at a rest area is not ideal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;His favorite blanket&lt;/strong&gt; — Familiar smells help anxious dogs settle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(For my full packing list, check out &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/road-trip-essentials-dogs&#34; &gt;road trip essentials for traveling with your dog&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-id-do-differently-the-crate-situation&#34;&gt;What I&amp;rsquo;d Do Differently: The Crate Situation
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I made the mistake of bringing Ansel&amp;rsquo;s wire crate to use in the hotel room. The problem? It rattled the entire drive. Every bump, every turn — rattle, rattle, rattle. Ansel is an anxious boy when it comes to weird sounds, so by the time we arrived, he was stressed and I was frustrated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The fix:&lt;/strong&gt; Get a crash-tested travel kennel that stays in the car.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two best options:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gunner Kennel&lt;/strong&gt; — The gold standard. 5-star crash test rating from the Center for Pet Safety, double-wall construction for temperature regulation, and built like a tank. For a 70-lb dog, you&amp;rsquo;d want the Large. They&amp;rsquo;re pricey (~$500+) and heavy (~72 lbs), but if safety is your priority, this is it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ruffland Kennel&lt;/strong&gt; — The more budget-friendly option (~$300-350). Single-piece roto-molded plastic, lighter weight, and performed well in crash testing when secured against the seatback. A lot of hunters and dog sport people swear by these.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Either way, your dog rides safer and you skip the rattling nightmare. I&amp;rsquo;m upgrading before my next trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;timing-tips&#34;&gt;Timing Tips
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leave early.&lt;/strong&gt; If you leave Jacksonville by 7am, you can be in PCB by early afternoon with plenty of stops.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plan for stops every 2 hours&lt;/strong&gt; — or whenever your dog tells you it&amp;rsquo;s time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Avoid Tallahassee rush hour&lt;/strong&gt; if possible (typically 4-6pm).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The last hour&lt;/strong&gt; (US-231 south into PCB) is the slowest part — two-lane roads and beach traffic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-bottom-line&#34;&gt;The Bottom Line
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is an easy drive if you plan for it. Pack smart, stop at Busy Bee, and invest in a proper travel crate. Your dog (and your sanity) will thank you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ready to book the hotel?&lt;/strong&gt; Check out my &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/embassy-suites-pcb-review&#34; &gt;Embassy Suites PCB review&lt;/a&gt; — it&amp;rsquo;s one of the best pet-friendly options in the area, and I booked it entirely on points.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
