<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Gear on ThePointsPup</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/gear/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Gear on ThePointsPup</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/gear/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Road Trip Essentials for Traveling with Your Dog</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/road-trip-essentials-dogs/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/road-trip-essentials-dogs/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve done enough road trips with Ansel to know what&amp;rsquo;s actually worth packing — and what just takes up space. Here&amp;rsquo;s my go-to list for traveling with a 70-pound dog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;car-setup&#34;&gt;Car Setup
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seat cover&lt;/strong&gt; — Non-negotiable. I use one in my 4Runner that covers the entire back seat, has flaps that protect the doors, and is waterproof. Saves your interior from muddy paws, sand, and the occasional drool puddle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Crate or barrier&lt;/strong&gt; — If your dog does better contained, a crash-tested crate is the safest option. Brands like Gunner and Ruff Land are pricey but built to protect your dog in an accident. If a crate doesn&amp;rsquo;t fit your setup, a car barrier keeps them in the back without roaming into the front seat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seat belt harness&lt;/strong&gt; — Another safety option if you don&amp;rsquo;t use a crate. Clips into your seatbelt and keeps your dog secured.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;food--water&#34;&gt;Food &amp;amp; Water
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Travel water bottle with bowl attachment&lt;/strong&gt; — This is the one thing I&amp;rsquo;d never skip. Mine has a bowl that screws onto the top, so I can give Ansel water at rest stops without digging through bags. Fits right in the cup holder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Collapsible bowls&lt;/strong&gt; — Cheap, packable, and useful for food or water at the hotel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Food storage&lt;/strong&gt; — I portion out food into ziplock bags or use a small airtight container. Keeps things simple and avoids lugging an entire bag of kibble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;comfort-items&#34;&gt;Comfort Items
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pet blanket&lt;/strong&gt; — Ansel has a designated travel blanket. It smells like home, which helps him settle in unfamiliar hotel rooms. Also useful for covering hotel furniture if you&amp;rsquo;re worried about fur.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Favorite toy&lt;/strong&gt; — Something familiar to keep them occupied during downtime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Treats&lt;/strong&gt; — For rewarding good behavior, training moments, and bribing them back into the car after a rest stop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;safety--cleanup&#34;&gt;Safety &amp;amp; Cleanup
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Poop bags&lt;/strong&gt; — I always overpack. Running out at a hotel or rest stop is not a situation you want to be in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pet first aid kit&lt;/strong&gt; — Basic stuff: bandages, antiseptic wipes, tweezers for ticks, Benadryl (ask your vet for dosage). You probably won&amp;rsquo;t need it, but you&amp;rsquo;ll be glad you have it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Towels&lt;/strong&gt; — At least one or two. For wet paws, muddy adventures, or unexpected messes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lint roller&lt;/strong&gt; — Your future self will thank you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;documents&#34;&gt;Documents
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vaccination records&lt;/strong&gt; — Some hotels ask for proof of rabies vaccination. Keep a copy on your phone or in the car.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ID tags&lt;/strong&gt; — Make sure your dog&amp;rsquo;s tags are up to date with your current phone number.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Microchip info&lt;/strong&gt; — Know your microchip number and make sure your contact info is current in the registry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-short-list&#34;&gt;The Short List
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re in a hurry, here&amp;rsquo;s the minimum:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Seat cover&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Water bottle with bowl&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Poop bags&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blanket&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Treats&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leash (obviously)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vaccination records&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything else is nice to have but not essential for a weekend trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;where-ive-used-this-stuff&#34;&gt;Where I&amp;rsquo;ve Used This Stuff
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most recently, Ansel and I did &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/pcb-embassy-suites-review&#34; &gt;5 nights in Panama City Beach&lt;/a&gt; — about a 5-hour drive from Jacksonville. This packing list kept us covered the whole trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Have a road trip essential I missed? &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/contact&#34; &gt;Let me know&lt;/a&gt; — I&amp;rsquo;m always looking to upgrade my setup.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
