<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Guides on ThePointsPup</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/guides/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Guides on ThePointsPup</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/guides/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Best Pet-Friendly Beach Towns Near Jacksonville</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/pet-friendly-beach-towns-jacksonville/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/pet-friendly-beach-towns-jacksonville/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Living in Jacksonville means you&amp;rsquo;re surrounded by beach towns worth exploring with your dog. Some are close enough for a lazy lunch. Others are worth a full weekend. Here are the spots Ansel and I keep coming back to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Hitting the road? Don&amp;rsquo;t forget to check out my &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/road-trip-essentials-dogs&#34; &gt;road trip essentials for traveling with your dog&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;jacksonville-beach&#34;&gt;Jacksonville Beach
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Drive time:&lt;/strong&gt; 25 minutes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t have to go far. Jax Beach has a ton of dog-friendly restaurants — over 40 according to BringFido — so finding a patio that welcomes your pup is never a problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One favorite is &lt;strong&gt;Salt Life Food Shack&lt;/strong&gt;, just three blocks from the beach. Dogs are welcome on the downstairs patio, and they&amp;rsquo;ll bring out a water bowl without you asking. Great surf-and-turf menu with tacos, sushi rolls, and fresh seafood. It&amp;rsquo;s casual, breezy, and Ansel always gets compliments from other diners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pro tip:&lt;/strong&gt; Go for a late lunch to beat the crowds. The patio fills up fast on weekends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;amelia-island&#34;&gt;Amelia Island
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Drive time:&lt;/strong&gt; 45 minutes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is one of the most dog-friendly spots in the area. The beaches allow leashed dogs, downtown Fernandina Beach has plenty of dog-friendly patios, and the whole island has a relaxed, walkable vibe. Great for a day trip or a quick overnight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One spot I always recommend is &lt;strong&gt;The Patio at 5th and Ash&lt;/strong&gt; — a casual American bistro with a beautiful outdoor patio under oak trees draped in Spanish moss. They&amp;rsquo;re genuinely dog-friendly and even have a dog menu with homemade biscuits. Ansel was &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; focused on earning one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pro tip:&lt;/strong&gt; If you&amp;rsquo;re staying overnight, check out the Hilton properties on the island. Some are pet-friendly and bookable on points. &lt;em&gt;(See my &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/best-credit-cards-pet-travelers&#34; &gt;credit cards guide&lt;/a&gt; for how I earn free nights.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;palm-coast--flagler-beach&#34;&gt;Palm Coast / Flagler Beach
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Drive time:&lt;/strong&gt; 1 hour 15 minutes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flagler Beach is low-key and locals love it. Dogs are allowed on the beach (leashed), and the pier area has a few casual spots to grab food. It&amp;rsquo;s less crowded than Daytona and has more of a small-town feel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a good &amp;ldquo;decompress&amp;rdquo; destination — not a ton of activities, just beach, food, and chill. Sometimes that&amp;rsquo;s exactly what you need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;new-smyrna-beach&#34;&gt;New Smyrna Beach
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Drive time:&lt;/strong&gt; 2 hours&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NSB has a great mix of beach access and dog-friendly dining. The vibe is artsy and laid-back — lots of murals, local shops, and good food.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One spot I always stop at is &lt;strong&gt;Yellow Dog Eats&lt;/strong&gt; — a funky sandwich shop with a big outdoor patio where dogs are welcome. The food is creative (think smoked meats, interesting sandwiches), and the whole place just feels like it was made for people who travel with their dogs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/restaurant-nsb2.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Ansel at Yellow Dog Eats&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 400px; border-radius: 12px; display: block; margin: 20px auto;&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ansel cooling off on the patio. That sign in the background says it all.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/restaurant-nsb.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Sharing a snack with Ansel&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 400px; border-radius: 12px; display: block; margin: 20px auto;&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;He&amp;rsquo;s very polite about sharing. Usually.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;daytona-beach&#34;&gt;Daytona Beach
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Drive time:&lt;/strong&gt; 1 hour 45 minutes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Daytona is hit or miss for dogs — the main beach doesn&amp;rsquo;t allow them during peak hours, but there are designated dog-friendly areas. The boardwalk area has some pet-friendly patios, and it&amp;rsquo;s a good base if you want to explore the surrounding towns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly, I usually skip Daytona proper and head to NSB or Flagler instead. But if you&amp;rsquo;re in the area, it&amp;rsquo;s worth a stop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;quick-reference&#34;&gt;Quick Reference
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;th&gt;Destination&lt;/th&gt;
          &lt;th&gt;Drive Time&lt;/th&gt;
          &lt;th&gt;Beach Access&lt;/th&gt;
          &lt;th&gt;Best For&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Jacksonville Beach&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;25 min&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Limited dog hours&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Quick lunch, tons of patios&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Amelia Island&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;45 min&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Leashed dogs allowed&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Day trip or weekend, walkable downtown&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Flagler Beach&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;1 hr 15 min&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Leashed dogs allowed&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Quiet beach day, low-key vibes&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;New Smyrna Beach&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;2 hrs&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Dog-friendly areas&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Artsy town, great food, worth a weekend&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Daytona Beach&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;1 hr 45 min&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Designated areas only&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Skip unless passing through&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-bottom-line&#34;&gt;The Bottom Line
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;All of these are easy drives from Jacksonville and make great trips with your dog. Pack a travel bag, book a pet-friendly hotel (on points, of course), and go explore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want more posts about the places we eat and stay?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;mailto:woof@thepointspup.com&#34; &gt;Shoot me an email&lt;/a&gt; and let me know what you&amp;rsquo;d like to see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read next:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/road-trip-essentials-dogs/&#34; &gt;Road Trip Essentials for Traveling with Your Dog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Jacksonville to Panama City Beach: A Pet-Friendly Road Trip Guide</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/jacksonville-to-panama-city-beach-road-trip/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/jacksonville-to-panama-city-beach-road-trip/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The drive from Jacksonville to Panama City Beach is about 5-7 hours depending on how many stops you make — and if you&amp;rsquo;re traveling with a dog, you&amp;rsquo;re going to make a lot of stops. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I learned driving this route with Ansel, my 70-pound GSP/Lab mix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Planning a PCB trip? Check out my full &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/embassy-suites-pcb-review&#34; &gt;Embassy Suites Panama City Beach review&lt;/a&gt; for the hotel details.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-route&#34;&gt;The Route
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;From Jacksonville (I started in Callahan), you&amp;rsquo;ll take I-10 West through Lake City, Tallahassee, and then head south on US-231 into Panama City Beach. It&amp;rsquo;s mostly highway driving with plenty of rest areas along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Distance:&lt;/strong&gt; ~350 miles&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Drive time:&lt;/strong&gt; 5-7 hours (with dog stops)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;best-stops-along-the-way&#34;&gt;Best Stops Along the Way
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-must-stop-busy-bee&#34;&gt;The Must-Stop: Busy Bee
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you only make one non-potty stop, make it &lt;strong&gt;Busy Bee&lt;/strong&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s basically Florida&amp;rsquo;s answer to Buc-ee&amp;rsquo;s — spotless restrooms (seriously, some of the cleanest gas station bathrooms you&amp;rsquo;ll ever see), a huge selection of snacks, jerky, fudge, and their famous Bee Bites. There&amp;rsquo;s also a Burger King and Dunkin&amp;rsquo; inside if you need real food.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two locations on I-10:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Live Oak&lt;/strong&gt; (Exit 283) — about 1.5 hours from Jacksonville&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lake City&lt;/strong&gt; (US-41 near I-75) — slightly earlier if you&amp;rsquo;re coming from the Callahan area&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both have plenty of room to walk your dog around before heading back on the road. It&amp;rsquo;s worth the stop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;rest-areas&#34;&gt;Rest Areas
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Florida&amp;rsquo;s I-10 rest areas are well-maintained with grassy pet areas:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Suwannee County Rest Area&lt;/strong&gt; (Mile Marker 294) — Good first stop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Madison County Rest Area&lt;/strong&gt; (Mile Marker 265) — Midway point&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leon County Rest Area&lt;/strong&gt; (Mile Marker 194) — Just west of Tallahassee&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All have pet areas, restrooms, and vending machines. Nothing fancy, but they get the job done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;coming-soon-buc-ees&#34;&gt;Coming Soon: Buc-ee&amp;rsquo;s
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Buc-ee&amp;rsquo;s is building a massive 75,000 square foot location near Tallahassee on I-10. Once that opens, it&amp;rsquo;ll be another great option. For now, Busy Bee has you covered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-i-packed-and-what-id-do-differently&#34;&gt;What I Packed (And What I&amp;rsquo;d Do Differently)
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-worked&#34;&gt;What Worked
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Backseat cover&lt;/strong&gt; — Non-negotiable. Keeps the car clean and gives your dog a non-slip surface.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Travel water bottle with attached bowl&lt;/strong&gt; — Perfect for rest stops without digging through bags.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Extra poop bags&lt;/strong&gt; — I always overpack. Running out at a rest area is not ideal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;His favorite blanket&lt;/strong&gt; — Familiar smells help anxious dogs settle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(For my full packing list, check out &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/road-trip-essentials-dogs&#34; &gt;road trip essentials for traveling with your dog&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-id-do-differently-the-crate-situation&#34;&gt;What I&amp;rsquo;d Do Differently: The Crate Situation
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I made the mistake of bringing Ansel&amp;rsquo;s wire crate to use in the hotel room. The problem? It rattled the entire drive. Every bump, every turn — rattle, rattle, rattle. Ansel is an anxious boy when it comes to weird sounds, so by the time we arrived, he was stressed and I was frustrated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The fix:&lt;/strong&gt; Get a crash-tested travel kennel that stays in the car.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two best options:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gunner Kennel&lt;/strong&gt; — The gold standard. 5-star crash test rating from the Center for Pet Safety, double-wall construction for temperature regulation, and built like a tank. For a 70-lb dog, you&amp;rsquo;d want the Large. They&amp;rsquo;re pricey (~$500+) and heavy (~72 lbs), but if safety is your priority, this is it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ruffland Kennel&lt;/strong&gt; — The more budget-friendly option (~$300-350). Single-piece roto-molded plastic, lighter weight, and performed well in crash testing when secured against the seatback. A lot of hunters and dog sport people swear by these.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Either way, your dog rides safer and you skip the rattling nightmare. I&amp;rsquo;m upgrading before my next trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;timing-tips&#34;&gt;Timing Tips
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leave early.&lt;/strong&gt; If you leave Jacksonville by 7am, you can be in PCB by early afternoon with plenty of stops.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plan for stops every 2 hours&lt;/strong&gt; — or whenever your dog tells you it&amp;rsquo;s time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Avoid Tallahassee rush hour&lt;/strong&gt; if possible (typically 4-6pm).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The last hour&lt;/strong&gt; (US-231 south into PCB) is the slowest part — two-lane roads and beach traffic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-bottom-line&#34;&gt;The Bottom Line
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is an easy drive if you plan for it. Pack smart, stop at Busy Bee, and invest in a proper travel crate. Your dog (and your sanity) will thank you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ready to book the hotel?&lt;/strong&gt; Check out my &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/embassy-suites-pcb-review&#34; &gt;Embassy Suites PCB review&lt;/a&gt; — it&amp;rsquo;s one of the best pet-friendly options in the area, and I booked it entirely on points.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Traveling with a Large Dog: Hotel Policies You Need to Know</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/traveling-with-large-dogs-hotel-policies/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/traveling-with-large-dogs-hotel-policies/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When you&amp;rsquo;re traveling with a small dog, finding pet-friendly hotels is pretty straightforward. But once your pup crosses that 50-pound threshold? Suddenly half your options disappear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I travel with Ansel, my 70-pound German Shorthaired Pointer/Lab mix. He&amp;rsquo;s a lanky, well-behaved sweetheart—but on paper, he&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;too big&amp;rdquo; for a lot of hotels. If you&amp;rsquo;re in the same boat with your large dog, here&amp;rsquo;s everything I&amp;rsquo;ve learned about navigating hotel weight limits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-weight-limit-problem&#34;&gt;The Weight Limit Problem
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most hotel chains set their pet weight limits between 50-75 pounds. The logic seems to be liability and room size, but the limits often feel arbitrary. A calm 80-pound Lab is going to cause fewer issues than a hyper 30-pound terrier, but policies don&amp;rsquo;t account for temperament.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what you&amp;rsquo;ll typically see:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Under 50 lbs&lt;/strong&gt;: Welcome almost everywhere&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;50-75 lbs&lt;/strong&gt;: Many options, but you&amp;rsquo;ll need to check policies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;75+ lbs&lt;/strong&gt;: Options get limited fast&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The good news? Several hotel chains have no weight limits at all, and others are more flexible than their official policies suggest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hotels-with-no-weight-limits&#34;&gt;Hotels with NO Weight Limits
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;These chains welcome dogs of any size—no awkward conversations at check-in required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;kimpton-hotels&#34;&gt;Kimpton Hotels
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The gold standard for large dog travel. Their unofficial motto is &amp;ldquo;if they fit through the door, they&amp;rsquo;re welcome.&amp;rdquo; They&amp;rsquo;ve hosted everything from Great Danes to llamas. No pet fee, no weight limit, and many properties have a resident &amp;ldquo;Director of Pet Relations&amp;rdquo; (a very good dog). The nightly wine reception often welcomes pups too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Best for&lt;/strong&gt;: Travelers who want a boutique experience and don&amp;rsquo;t mind paying more per night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;motel-6--studio-6&#34;&gt;Motel 6 / Studio 6
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The most budget-friendly option for large dogs. No pet fee at Motel 6, and no weight or breed restrictions. Studio 6 (their extended stay brand) charges around $10/night but still has no size limit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Best for&lt;/strong&gt;: Road trippers who need affordable, no-questions-asked pet lodging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;la-quinta&#34;&gt;La Quinta
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;La Quinta used to be the holy grail—no pet fee and no weight limit. Since Wyndham acquired them, policies vary more by location. Many still have no restrictions, but some now cap at 75 pounds with a $25/night fee. Always call ahead to confirm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Best for&lt;/strong&gt;: Frequent travelers who want consistency and don&amp;rsquo;t mind calling to verify.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;red-roof-inn&#34;&gt;Red Roof Inn
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;No weight limit, no breed restrictions, and no pet fee. They also provide designated dog walk areas with waste bags at each location. A solid budget option that genuinely welcomes large dogs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Best for&lt;/strong&gt;: Budget road trips where you want a pet-friendly guarantee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;loews-hotels&#34;&gt;Loews Hotels
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;All 24 Loews properties accept dogs of any size. The &amp;ldquo;Loews Loves Pets&amp;rdquo; program provides beds, bowls, treats, and even a room service menu for dogs. Fees vary by property but are typically reasonable for the upscale experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Best for&lt;/strong&gt;: Special occasions when you want to treat yourself and your pup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;sonesta-all-brands&#34;&gt;Sonesta (All Brands)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Royal Sonesta, Sonesta Hotels, Sonesta Select, Sonesta ES Suites, and Sonesta Simply Suites all allow pets with no breed or size limit. Standard fee is $75 per stay (or $150 for stays over 7 nights).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Best for&lt;/strong&gt;: Extended stays and business travel with your dog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hotels-with-75-80-lb-limits&#34;&gt;Hotels with 75-80 lb Limits
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;If your dog is in the 50-80 pound range, these chains will likely work:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;th&gt;Chain&lt;/th&gt;
          &lt;th&gt;Weight Limit&lt;/th&gt;
          &lt;th&gt;Pet Fee&lt;/th&gt;
          &lt;th&gt;Notes&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Best Western&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;80 lbs per dog&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;~$30/night&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Policies vary by location&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Drury Hotels&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;80 lbs combined&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;$50/night&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Up to 2 pets&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Candlewood Suites&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;80 lbs&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;$75-150/stay&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;IHG property&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;My Place Hotels&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;80 lbs&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;$15-30/night&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Midwest-focused chain&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Extended Stay America&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;36&amp;quot; x 36&amp;quot;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Varies&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Measures by size, not weight!&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pro tip&lt;/strong&gt;: Extended Stay America measures dogs by dimensions rather than weight. If your dog is under 36 inches tall and 36 inches long, you&amp;rsquo;re good—that covers most large breeds except giant breeds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-about-hilton&#34;&gt;What About Hilton?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since I focus a lot on Hilton for points travel, here&amp;rsquo;s the reality: most Hilton brands cap at 50-75 pounds, and it varies by property.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hilton brands that tend to be more flexible&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Home2 Suites (75 lb limit)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hilton Garden Inn (75 lb limit at most locations)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Homewood Suites (75 lb limit)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DoubleTree (varies widely—some have no limit)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Canopy by Hilton (very pet-friendly, 50-75 lbs)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Always call the specific property&lt;/strong&gt; before booking. The website might say 50 pounds, but the front desk often has discretion—especially for well-behaved dogs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re earning Hilton points for pet travel, check out my &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/hilton-credit-card-quiz/&#34; &gt;Hilton credit card quiz&lt;/a&gt; to find the right card for your travel style.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tips-for-when-your-dog-exceeds-the-limit&#34;&gt;Tips for When Your Dog Exceeds the Limit
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned from traveling with a dog who&amp;rsquo;s technically &amp;ldquo;too big&amp;rdquo; for some policies:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-call-the-hotel-directly&#34;&gt;1. Call the hotel directly
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t just book online and hope for the best. Call the front desk, explain your dog&amp;rsquo;s size and temperament, and ask if they can accommodate you. Many hotels will say yes even if the official policy says no—they care more about behavior than the number on the scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-be-honest&#34;&gt;2. Be honest
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t lie about your dog&amp;rsquo;s weight. If you show up with an obviously-larger-than-stated dog, you risk being turned away. Honesty builds trust and often gets you further than trying to sneak by.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-mention-good-behavior&#34;&gt;3. Mention good behavior
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;He&amp;rsquo;s 70 pounds but very calm and well-trained&amp;rdquo; goes a long way. Hotels worry about noise complaints and damage—if you can reassure them your dog won&amp;rsquo;t cause issues, they&amp;rsquo;re more likely to flex on the weight limit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-offer-a-larger-deposit&#34;&gt;4. Offer a larger deposit
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;If a hotel is hesitant, offering to put down a larger refundable deposit can ease their concerns. It shows you&amp;rsquo;re confident in your dog&amp;rsquo;s behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;5-book-pet-friendly-room-types&#34;&gt;5. Book pet-friendly room types
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some hotels have designated pet rooms that can accommodate larger dogs. Ask specifically about these when you call.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;6-use-bringfido&#34;&gt;6. Use BringFido
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.bringfido.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;BringFido&lt;/a&gt; is the best resource for finding genuinely pet-friendly hotels. They verify policies and can even help negotiate weight limit exceptions through their Canine Concierge service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-reality-check&#34;&gt;The Reality Check
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hotels rarely actually weigh dogs. Most front desk staff will eyeball your pup and decide if they&amp;rsquo;re comfortable. A well-groomed, calm dog on a leash makes a much better impression than a dog that&amp;rsquo;s pulling and barking—regardless of size.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, don&amp;rsquo;t abuse this. If a hotel says 50 pounds and you show up with a 120-pound Mastiff, you&amp;rsquo;re putting the staff in an awkward position and potentially ruining it for other large-dog travelers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-go-to-strategy&#34;&gt;My Go-To Strategy
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;For road trips with Ansel, here&amp;rsquo;s my approach:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First choice&lt;/strong&gt;: La Quinta or Red Roof Inn (no restrictions, budget-friendly)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If I want something nicer&lt;/strong&gt;: Kimpton or Loews (splurge-worthy, genuinely welcoming)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If using Hilton points&lt;/strong&gt;: Home2 Suites or Homewood Suites (call ahead to confirm)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Always&lt;/strong&gt;: Call the specific property before booking to confirm they&amp;rsquo;ll welcome my 70-pound guy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-bottom-line&#34;&gt;The Bottom Line
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Traveling with a large dog takes more planning, but it&amp;rsquo;s absolutely doable. The key is knowing which chains are genuinely welcoming versus which ones just tolerate pets. Stick with the no-weight-limit chains for stress-free bookings, and always call ahead when you&amp;rsquo;re unsure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your big dog deserves adventures too. Don&amp;rsquo;t let arbitrary weight limits keep you home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Have a favorite hotel chain for large dogs? I&amp;rsquo;d love to hear about it— see my &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/contact/&#34; &gt;contact page&lt;/a&gt; to reach out.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read next:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/why-hilton-for-pet-travelers/&#34; &gt;Why Hilton Is the Best Hotel Chain for Pet Travelers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Why Hilton Is the Best Hotel Chain for Pet Travelers</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/why-hilton-for-pet-travelers/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/why-hilton-for-pet-travelers/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When I started traveling with Ansel, my 70-pound GSP/Lab mix, I quickly learned that not all hotel chains are created equal. Some properties say they&amp;rsquo;re &amp;ldquo;pet-friendly&amp;rdquo; but hit you with breed restrictions, weight limits, or fees that make you feel like your dog isn&amp;rsquo;t actually welcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hilton is different. Here&amp;rsquo;s why it&amp;rsquo;s become my go-to for pet travel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;every-hilton-brand-welcomes-dogs&#34;&gt;Every Hilton Brand Welcomes Dogs
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the big one. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re staying at a Hampton Inn on a road trip or splurging on a Waldorf Astoria for a special occasion, &lt;strong&gt;every Hilton brand in the U.S. accepts pets&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That consistency matters when you&amp;rsquo;re planning trips with a dog. No more calling ahead to individual properties hoping they&amp;rsquo;ll say yes. No more getting turned away at check-in because someone didn&amp;rsquo;t update the website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The brands include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hampton Inn &amp;amp; Suites&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hilton Garden Inn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Home2 Suites&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Homewood Suites&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DoubleTree&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Embassy Suites&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hilton Hotels &amp;amp; Resorts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Canopy by Hilton&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Curio Collection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tapestry Collection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conrad Hotels&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Waldorf Astoria&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One caveat:&lt;/strong&gt; Weight limits vary by property, typically ranging from 50-75 lbs. If you have a larger dog, always call ahead to confirm. Check out my &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/traveling-with-large-dogs-hotel-policies/&#34; &gt;guide to traveling with large dogs&lt;/a&gt; for more tips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;points-are-easy-to-earn&#34;&gt;Points Are Easy to Earn
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hilton points are some of the easiest hotel points to stack through everyday spending. With the right credit card, you can earn points on:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Groceries (including all that dog food)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gas stations (road trip fuel-ups)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Restaurants (dog-friendly patios count!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vet bills and pet supplies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everything else&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve booked multiple free nights at pet-friendly Hiltons without setting foot in a hotel — just from everyday spending on my Hilton credit card.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Not sure which card is right for you?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/hilton-credit-card-quiz/&#34; &gt;Take my quick quiz&lt;/a&gt; to find your perfect match.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;diamond-status-makes-pet-travel-easier&#34;&gt;Diamond Status Makes Pet Travel Easier
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hilton&amp;rsquo;s top-tier status, Diamond, comes with perks that are especially valuable when you&amp;rsquo;re traveling with a dog:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Room upgrades&lt;/strong&gt; — More space means more room for your pup to spread out. I&amp;rsquo;ve been upgraded to suites multiple times, and the extra square footage makes a huge difference with a 70-pound dog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Late checkout&lt;/strong&gt; — Morning potty breaks, packing up dog gear, loading the car&amp;hellip; it all takes longer with a pet. Late checkout (often until 2pm) gives you breathing room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Daily food &amp;amp; beverage credit&lt;/strong&gt; — Pet fees add up. Having your meals partially covered helps offset those costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Executive lounge access&lt;/strong&gt; — A quiet spot to grab coffee or a snack, away from the chaos of the main lobby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best part? You don&amp;rsquo;t have to stay 60 nights a year to get Diamond. The &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/hilton-diamond-status-guide/&#34; &gt;Hilton Aspire card&lt;/a&gt; gives you automatic Diamond status just for having the card.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;pet-fees-are-reasonable&#34;&gt;Pet Fees Are Reasonable
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hilton pet fees typically range from $50-$95 per stay, depending on the brand and location. That&amp;rsquo;s middle-of-the-road for the industry — not the cheapest, but far from the worst offenders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you&amp;rsquo;re booking on points, the pet fee is often your only out-of-pocket cost. I&amp;rsquo;ll happily pay $75 for a &amp;ldquo;free&amp;rdquo; hotel stay at a property I know will welcome my dog without hassle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-hilton-pet-travel-stack&#34;&gt;My Hilton Pet Travel Stack
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the setup I use for earning and booking pet-friendly Hilton stays:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hilton Aspire Card&lt;/strong&gt; — Automatic Diamond status, annual free night certificate, $400 resort credit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hilton Points&lt;/strong&gt; — Earned from everyday spending, used for free nights&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5th Night Free&lt;/strong&gt; — Book 4 nights on points, get the 5th free (20% savings!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BringFido&lt;/strong&gt; — For double-checking pet policies and weight limits at specific properties&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This combo has gotten me free stays at pet-friendly Embassy Suites, Hilton Garden Inns, and more — with Ansel welcome at every single one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ready-to-start&#34;&gt;Ready to Start?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re new to Hilton points and want to start traveling free with your pup, here&amp;rsquo;s where to begin:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/hilton-credit-card-quiz/&#34; &gt;Take the quiz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to find the right Hilton credit card for your travel style&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/hilton-diamond-status-guide/&#34; &gt;Learn about Diamond status&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and why it&amp;rsquo;s worth pursuing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/best-credit-cards-pet-travelers/&#34; &gt;Compare all the credit card options&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; if you want the full breakdown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have questions? &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/contact/&#34; &gt;Reach out&lt;/a&gt; — I&amp;rsquo;m always happy to help fellow pet travelers figure out the points game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Traveling with a pup over 50 lbs? Read my &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/traveling-with-large-dogs-hotel-policies/&#34; &gt;guide to hotel policies for large dogs&lt;/a&gt; before you book.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Road Trip Essentials for Traveling with Your Dog</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/road-trip-essentials-dogs/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/road-trip-essentials-dogs/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve done enough road trips with Ansel to know what&amp;rsquo;s actually worth packing — and what just takes up space. Here&amp;rsquo;s my go-to list for traveling with a 70-pound dog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-car-setup&#34;&gt;🚗 Car Setup
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seat cover&lt;/strong&gt; — Non-negotiable. I use one in my 4Runner that covers the entire back seat, has flaps that protect the doors, and is waterproof. Saves your interior from muddy paws, sand, and the occasional drool puddle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Crash-tested crate&lt;/strong&gt; — If your dog does better contained, a crate is the safest option. Brands like Gunner and Ruff Land are pricey but built to protect your dog in an accident. Worth it for peace of mind on long drives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Car barrier&lt;/strong&gt; — If a crate doesn&amp;rsquo;t fit your setup, a barrier keeps them in the back without roaming into the front seat. Less secure than a crate, but better than nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seat belt harness&lt;/strong&gt; — Another safety option if you don&amp;rsquo;t use a crate. Clips into your seatbelt and keeps your dog secured. Look for crash-tested options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-food--water&#34;&gt;💧 Food &amp;amp; Water
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Travel water bottle with bowl attachment&lt;/strong&gt; — This is the one thing I&amp;rsquo;d never skip. Mine has a bowl that screws onto the top, so I can give Ansel water at rest stops without digging through bags. Fits right in the cup holder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Collapsible bowls&lt;/strong&gt; — Cheap, packable, and useful for food or water at the hotel. I keep a couple in my bag at all times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Food storage&lt;/strong&gt; — I portion out food into ziplock bags or use a small airtight container. Keeps things simple and avoids lugging an entire bag of kibble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-comfort-items&#34;&gt;🛏️ Comfort Items
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pet blanket&lt;/strong&gt; — Ansel has a designated travel blanket. It smells like home, which helps him settle in unfamiliar hotel rooms. Also useful for covering hotel furniture if you&amp;rsquo;re worried about fur.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Favorite toy&lt;/strong&gt; — Something familiar to keep them occupied during downtime. Don&amp;rsquo;t bring anything too squeaky unless you want to hear it for 5 hours straight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Treats&lt;/strong&gt; — For rewarding good behavior, training moments, and bribing them back into the car after a rest stop. I pack more than I think I&amp;rsquo;ll need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-safety--cleanup&#34;&gt;🧹 Safety &amp;amp; Cleanup
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Poop bags&lt;/strong&gt; — I always overpack. Running out at a hotel or rest stop is not a situation you want to be in. Bring twice as many as you think you need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pet first aid kit&lt;/strong&gt; — Basic stuff: bandages, antiseptic wipes, tweezers for ticks, Benadryl (ask your vet for dosage). You probably won&amp;rsquo;t need it, but you&amp;rsquo;ll be glad you have it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Towels&lt;/strong&gt; — At least one or two. For wet paws, muddy adventures, post-beach shakeoffs, or unexpected messes. Old towels work great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lint roller&lt;/strong&gt; — Your future self will thank you. Keep one in the car and one in your bag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-documents&#34;&gt;📋 Documents
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vaccination records&lt;/strong&gt; — Some hotels ask for proof of rabies vaccination. Keep a copy on your phone or in the car. I take a photo of Ansel&amp;rsquo;s records so I always have them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ID tags&lt;/strong&gt; — Make sure your dog&amp;rsquo;s tags are up to date with your current phone number. Travel is the worst time for a tag with an old number.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Microchip info&lt;/strong&gt; — Know your microchip number and make sure your contact info is current in the registry. Takes 5 minutes to check online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-the-quick-packing-checklist&#34;&gt;✅ The Quick Packing Checklist
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re in a hurry, here&amp;rsquo;s the minimum:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;th&gt;Essential&lt;/th&gt;
          &lt;th&gt;Why&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;🚗 Seat cover&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Protect your car&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;💧 Water bottle with bowl&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Hydration at rest stops&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;💩 Poop bags (lots)&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t run out&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;🛏️ Blanket&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Comfort + furniture protection&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;🦴 Treats&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Bribes work&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;🦮 Leash&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Obviously&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;📋 Vaccination records&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Hotels may ask&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything else is nice to have but not essential for a weekend trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-where-ive-used-this-stuff&#34;&gt;🐾 Where I&amp;rsquo;ve Used This Stuff
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most recently, Ansel and I did &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/pcb-embassy-suites-review&#34; &gt;5 nights in Panama City Beach&lt;/a&gt; — about a 5-hour drive from Jacksonville. This packing list kept us covered the whole trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The seat cover handled sandy paws after the beach, the water bottle was a lifesaver at rest stops, and the blanket made the hotel room feel like home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-my-gear-recommendations&#34;&gt;🛒 My Gear Recommendations
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what I personally use:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;th&gt;Item&lt;/th&gt;
          &lt;th&gt;What I Use&lt;/th&gt;
          &lt;th&gt;Notes&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Seat cover&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Waterproof hammock-style&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Covers doors too&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Water bottle&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Bottle with flip-up bowl&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Cup holder friendly&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Crate&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Gunner G1&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Pricey but bombproof&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;First aid kit&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Pre-made pet kit + Benadryl&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Check with your vet on dosage&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Blanket&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Old fleece blanket&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Smells like home&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Affiliate links coming soon — I&amp;rsquo;ll update this post once I&amp;rsquo;m partnered with Amazon.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Have a road trip essential I missed? &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/contact&#34; &gt;Let me know&lt;/a&gt; — I&amp;rsquo;m always looking to upgrade my setup.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read next:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/pet-friendly-beach-towns-jacksonville/&#34; &gt;Best Pet-Friendly Beach Towns Near Jacksonville&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
